<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Colombia | The Other Radio]]></title>
  <link href="http://jcruiz.co/blog/categories/colombia/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jcruiz.co/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-26T20:52:52-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://jcruiz.co/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Juan Camilo Ruiz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The New Era of Colombian Innovators is here]]></title>
    <link href="http://jcruiz.co/blog/2014/09/28/the-new-era-of-colombian-innovators-is-here/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-28T22:34:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jcruiz.co/blog/2014/09/28/the-new-era-of-colombian-innovators-is-here</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Byqgbw4IcAAltGw.jpg" alt="courtesy of @SWCol" />
In recent weeks I’ve virtually followed 2 StartupWeekend events that took place in Bogota, Colombia that gave me a general ideal about the growth of the innovation ecosystem in the country and the new blood of entrepreneurs. </p>

<p>I noticed something that is establishing as a strong and valid alternative that attracts young generations to come up with a fearless attitude and bring fresh and new ideas to improve the way things work in the country/city/communities. In this article I’m going to offer my negative and positive impressions together with resources that are useful for anyone that wants to followup on this.<br />
<!--more-->
###Event 1: StartupWeekend Uniandes
I found out about a <a href="http://uniandes.startupweekend.org/">startup-weekend Uniandes</a> event that took place at the no.1 ranked school in the country. And I was positive surprise that they had a live stream.</p>

<p>My main goal was to get a sense of the dynamics and quality of the projects/mentors/judges to compare it against the events that is normal to see all the time in the silicon valley.
###Event 2: StartupWeekend Fashion Tech
Having a more defined objective into exploring the challenges and ideas presented on a fields like eCommerce which I’ve been exposed while working at Moovweb. This in combination with a very developed and strong fashion industry in Colombia attracted me to also follow this event via streaming.
####What I liked?
<strong>Organization:</strong> I was positively impressed on how well the events were organized. Bringing together participants, mentors, sponsors and judges during a full weekend event is not an easy tasks. And on top of that, opening up the events for people that couldn’t not make it in person via streaming was fantastic.
<strong>Ideas:</strong> A lot of new and interesting initiatives were explored, also with the guidance of the mentors the refinement between where it starts and what gets presented to the judges is actually, in the majority of the cases, something that is well scoped.
<strong>Open communication:</strong> Not just among mentors, participants and organizers, but also I, as remote attendee had the opportunity to interact with many people via twitter and send feedback almost in real time as if I was there.
<strong>Social conscience:</strong> Colombia’s own reality and timing is crucial, we are entering to an era where peace in the nation seems like a viable solution. Though this brings many challenges for the civil society. I really like to see a few mentors trying to push the participants towards generating ideas that contribute with social ideas instead of the “social garbage”. There is a big opportunity for innovation and something that is unique to the innovation environment in Colombia.
####Things that need improvement
<strong>Presentation skills:</strong> Something that really makes a difference on pitching an idea is the presentation skills. Generally speaking the in the US people start building this skills at very early stages in life. As opposed to in the last minute and without much form.
<strong>Sponsors:</strong> There not enough exposition/involvement of sponsors to these events. The judges are good but, involving the industry and companies that would benefit from the amazing ideas that this young people are creating is a great business opportunity. I noticed the same as I was in college: the gap between the schools and the market is big in countries like Colombia.
<strong>Wider exposure:</strong> In some cases I could see that companies and ideas focused on a really small subset of competitors in ideas that are already in the market. Pushing the local entrepreneurs to know the space and know it well has to be a measure of success.
<strong>Large groups:</strong> Many of the groups seems really big,. It’s hard to start something or give continuity having too many people to coordinate with.</p>

<p>Coincidencially at the time of writing this article I bumped into this article on LinkedIn called <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/article/20140822204819-17275377-a-call-for-early-stage-investment-in-colombia">A call for early stage investment in Colombia</a> that touches in many of the aspects that I mentioned in this article.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Traveling to Bogota? Here are my recommendations part 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://jcruiz.co/blog/2014/03/02/traveling-to-bogota-here-are-my-recommendations-part-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-02T17:06:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jcruiz.co/blog/2014/03/02/traveling-to-bogota-here-are-my-recommendations-part-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been asked in various occasions for recommendations and tips when traveling to Colombia. The people that know me, are aware that I talk a lot about Colombia and about my life growing in Bogota. </p>

<p>Conversations about Colombia, often end up in someone knowing someone that have been to Colombia or is planning to go to Colombia. And often, I end up volunteering to provide tips, guidance to get what I consider, an awesome experience while in my Country.</p>

<p>So instead of continuing sending out individual messages with recommendations about Colombia, why not posting them out there in the Internet so other could potentially find them? So here they are, let’s start with my city: Bogota
<!--more-->
Bogota is a very large city that much like any other major city in the world like NYC, Paris or Sao Paulo is live 24x7. These days the traffic has been really bad so be prepared to spend time in traffic jams, so avoid as much as you can to move around during peak times. 7 - 9 a.m in the mornings and 4-7 at night.</p>

<p>If you have a smarthphone with an active data plan on your phone. I encourage you to download <a href="http://tappsi.co/">Tappsi</a>, so you can order taxis in a similar way to Lift or Uber in a secure and confortable way. Also, <a href="https://www.uber.com/cities/bogota">Uber</a> is active in Bogota and the prices similar to the US.</p>

<p>I’m going to start covering those areas in the city that are located in the northen part:</p>

<h3 id="usaquen">Usaquen</h3>
<p style="text-align: center; font-weight: bold;">What used to be a small town located in the outskirts of the city, it's now a neighborhood. Though it is one of the most vibrant areas where you can find great restaurants and bars. You could literally try different things in every visit.</p>
<p><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v204/juanchoruiz/blog/usaquen_zpsbfe09de2.jpg"></p>

<p>Recommendations:<br />
Usaquen has a famous flea market on Sundays where you can experience the great diversity of Bogota and buy really good handcrafts and souvenirs. Also right next to Usaquen there is a nice shopping mall-Hacienda Santa Barbara.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Antara: Peruvian food.</li>
  <li>80 sillas: Fusion international.</li>
  <li>Abasto: Organic/colombian food, great for brunch.</li>
  <li>Bogota Beer company: Drinks, social fun times.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="parque-93">Parque 93</h3>
<p style="text-align: center; font-weight: bold;">A park in the north that is surrounded by nice bars and restaurants. A great place to go for dinner + drinks/party</p>
<p><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v204/juanchoruiz/blog/93_zps71f8cfa8.jpg"></p>

<p>Recommendations:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Salto del Angel: Dinner + party</li>
  <li>Sagal: Steak house</li>
  <li>Bogota Beer company</li>
  <li>Wok: Asian fusion</li>
  <li>La Hamburgueseria: Burgers + live music</li>
  <li>El corral: If you like hamburgers, you <strong>HAVE TO</strong> try El Corral, the best burgers in the world</li>
  <li>La bonga del sinu: Colombian style stake house</li>
  <li>Kukaramakara: Party</li>
  <li>Gaira Cafe: Northern Colombian food + party</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="zona-t">Zona T</h3>
<p style="text-align: center; font-weight: bold;">Is Bogota's version of San Francisco's Union Square. Upscale shopping + tons of alternatives to eat and party</p>
<p><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v204/juanchoruiz/blog/zonaT_zps0aaf280e.jpg"></p>

<p>Recommendations:</p>

<ul>
  <li>La Plaza de Andres: Great food from all over Colombia</li>
  <li>14 Incas: Peruvian</li>
  <li>La mona: After-party food</li>
  <li>Andres DC: One of the best parties in the city you can get food there as well</li>
  <li>Cachao: Mojitos + live salsa</li>
  <li>Brasserie: French</li>
  <li>Armando Records: Alternative music, live bands, party</li>
  <li>Club Colombia: Upscale colombian food</li>
  <li>Wabisabi: Japanese</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="zona-g">Zona G</h3>
<p style="text-align: center; font-weight: bold;">Established as one of the fastest growing areas for new and upscale restaurants in the city.</p>
<p><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v204/juanchoruiz/blog/zonag_zps890c7f10.jpg"></p>

<p>Recommendations:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Astrid y Gaston: Peruvian</li>
  <li>La Bagatelle: French</li>
  <li>La Cigale: Frech</li>
  <li>La Biferia: Steakhouse</li>
  <li>Masa: Bakery, coffee</li>
  <li>Nazca: Peruvian</li>
</ul>

<p>Part 2 with other areas of the city comming up soon…</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
