<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: XBMC | The Other Radio]]></title>
  <link href="http://young-bastion-9487.herokuapp.com//blog/categories/xbmc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://young-bastion-9487.herokuapp.com//"/>
  <updated>2014-02-19T14:57:52-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://young-bastion-9487.herokuapp.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Juan Camilo Ruiz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The No-Cable Era: A geek's perspective]]></title>
    <link href="http://young-bastion-9487.herokuapp.com//blog/2014/02/19/the-no-cable-era/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-19T00:40:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://young-bastion-9487.herokuapp.com//blog/2014/02/19/the-no-cable-era</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s been almost 4 years that I cut cable tv at home. For some, it could sound as if I&rsquo;m being cheap but the reality is that I keep on finding more and more people that decide to stop paying for cable as we don&rsquo;t really see the benefit from such service.</p>

<h2>The On-demand Content Era</h2>

<p>If I have to admit something that I&rsquo;ve missed in these years, maybe that is some of the live events like sports, the oscars, season finales, etc. Yet most of the times these are all aired on public tv channels. That in my mind means: not need to pay for a service where most of the time is spent by watching the channels that are already free.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>In most cases, at least in the US, it&rsquo;s not hard to find a free official streaming services for the majority of free channels. I believe that media networks have understood that at least by publishing a free stream online, they can regain control over publishing advertising.</p>

<p>No more commercials! Definitely that&rsquo;s something that I don&rsquo;t miss at all. I still &ldquo;consume&rdquo; advertising but not to the extent that I used to when I had cable TV. After having Netflix, Hulu and, XBMC I compleately moved away from being expose to tons of advertising, now I decide what and when to consume advertising.</p>

<h2>TV for Geeks at Home</h2>

<p>Another reason why I don&rsquo;t pay for cable is because I realized that even if I had 200, 300 or 50 channels available, I would spend 90% of my time watching the same 5 channels. In my case, those are all sports related channels. And, one of my biggest quests since comming to the US has been finding good quality <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Football">Football</a> channel.</p>

<p>Looking at many alternatives, a friend of mine pointed me to the <a href="http://xbmc.org">XBMC</a> project that offers a full blown open source media server, by which you can access content located within a network.</p>

<p>After buying my first <a href="http://raspberrypi.org">Raspberry PI</a>, I was able to install the XBMC version that has been ported to this hardware called &ndash; <a href="http://www.raspbmc.com">Raspbmc</a>. Now using the some XBMC plugins, I&rsquo;m able to access a lot of on-demand, live content and output them direclty to my TV via HDMI.</p>

<p>So far my favorite plugins are:</p>

<ul>
<li>LiveStreams &ndash; I&rsquo;m able to access football worlwide. Checkout <a href="www.pluginsxbmc.com">www.pluginsxbmc.com</a></li>
<li>Bluecop &ndash; Brings the nice HD streaming from ESPN 3 (Tennis opens, woot!)</li>
<li>P2P Stream/AceStreams &ndash; In combination with Livestreams, you could access many HD streams for live sports.</li>
<li>FTV &ndash; I access CBS,NBC, CNBC streamings in the US as well as many public channels</li>
</ul>


<p>This in combination with Netflix, Hulu and soon HBO Go, allow me to have the content I want, whenever I want. For any news and world affairs Internet both written and listened (TuneIn or Sticher) are my best friends.</p>

<h2>Do you still pay for Cable? Why?</h2>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
