<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: installation | The Other Radio]]></title>
  <link href="http://jcruiz.co/blog/categories/installation/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jcruiz.co/"/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
  <updated>2017-03-22T00:40:45-07:00</updated>
=======
  <updated>2017-09-19T21:35:53-07:00</updated>
>>>>>>> staging
  <id>http://jcruiz.co/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Juan Camilo Ruiz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Installing Chrome on RHEL6.3]]></title>
    <link href="http://jcruiz.co/blog/2013/10/03/installing-chrome-on-rhel6-dot-3/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-03T00:04:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jcruiz.co/blog/2013/10/03/installing-chrome-on-rhel6-dot-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Facing an interesting task the other day at work. Install <a href="https://www.google.com/intl/en/chrome/browser/">Google Chrome</a> in a RHEL6.3 machine. This seems like a pretty standard task to be perfomed. </p>

<p>Interesting enough, Google is not longer supporting RedHat-based linux flavors such as CentOS or Fedora. This to me is actually shocking at the same time that compleately puts my engenieering ego in the spot.
<!--more-->
After googling around for hours I managed to get it working. Thank to <a href="http://chrome.richardlloyd.org.uk/">Richar Lloyd</a> and <a href="http://www.tecmint.com/install-google-chrome-on-redhat-centos-fedora-linux/">Narad Shrestha</a>, I was able to see the light at the end of the tunnel.</p>

<p>So follow up the above link from Naradm, then it will prompt you to upgrade the entire system to a new version in order to run chrome, which really is ridiculous - instead just upgrade nss by doing:</p>

<p><code>yum update nss</code></p>

<p>after that you will be able to execute google-chrome as a non-root user.</p>

<p>Also as a recommendation, enter your RHN credential directly during installation, as this is the only way to get YUM up and running without a problem. Otherwhise you will get stuck trying to run commands in the terminal + searching for the right wizard that allows you to register you machine into the RHN.</p>

<p>Mission accomplished </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
