<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: traveling | The Other Radio]]></title>
  <link href="http://jcruiz.co/blog/categories/traveling/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jcruiz.co/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-28T16:38:09-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://jcruiz.co/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Juan Camilo Ruiz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[En La Copa, Brasil demuestra su potencial una vez más]]></title>
    <link href="http://jcruiz.co/blog/2014/07/15/en-la-copa/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-15T20:20:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jcruiz.co/blog/2014/07/15/en-la-copa</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>En días pasados tuve la oportunidad de escribir un artículo para la revista <a href="http://macmagazine.com.br">Mac Magazine Brasil</a> en el que comparto mi perspectiva después de haber asistido a la copa del mundo en Brasil, narrando las similitudes que encuentro con Colombia alrededor del potencial que nuestros países tienen en un mundo donde las fronteras están cada vez más cerca.
<!--more-->
Pode encontrar a versão no português aqui
<a href="http://macmagazine.com.br/2014/07/15/appreendedor-na-copa-do-mundo-brasil-demonstra-o-seu-potencial-mais-uma-vez/">http://macmagazine.com.br/2014/07/15/appreendedor-na-copa-do-mundo-brasil-demonstra-o-seu-potencial-mais-uma-vez/</a></p>

<p>Durante algunas semanas tuve la oportunidad maravillosa de disfrutar de la copa del mundo en distintas ciudades a lo largo de Brasil, ya una vez de regreso al valle de silicio, comparto algunas impresiones que me dejó esta copa dejando de un lado el tema deportivo y enfocándose en el potencial que tiene Brasil para continuar evolucionando a la par de los que consideramos los “mejores” países.</p>

<p>La copa del mundo estuvo precedida de dificultades, polémicas, escándalos y se generó la expectativa de  un fracaso anunciado. Desde mi perspectiva Brasil y los brasileños lograron llevar a cabo una de las mejores copas de la historia en lo que a fútbol se refiere dentro de un ambiente de fiesta y alegría única característica del pueblo brasileño. A la altura de cualquier otro país que está en vía de desarrollo.</p>

<p>Quedo demostrado el enorme potencial que Brasil tiene para competir a la par de cualquier otro país y este nivel de competitividad se puede desarrollar en cualquier campo - no solo en el ámbito de los deportes.Brasil cuenta ya con muchas aspectos fundamentales de competitividad: infraestructura en las ciudades, buenas vías terrestres, puertos marítimos, internet de alta velocidad, aeropuertos que conectan todos los puntos del país y con el exterior, etc. </p>

<p>Así mismo Brasil está experimentando una explosión tecnológica que toca todos los sectores de la sociedad, los brasileños son naturales para las redes sociales y el mundo móvil está transformando la forma en que se acceden y utilizan servicios a nivel local y nacional.</p>

<p>No soy un experto en los problemas de fondo que enfrenta Brasil, sin embargo noto muchas similitudes con relación a mi país Colombia así como otros de la región. Allí la cultura no se enfoca en innovar con calidad, por el contrario siempre se espera que algo no funcione de la forma en que debería funcionar desde el principio y esto es aceptado, se cree que lo de afuera es mejor y tiene mejor calidad y creemos que por estar en América del Sur no tenemos las mismas oportunidades.</p>

<p>Las barreras están en nuestra mente y en nuestra cultura - apostemos al buen trabajo, al trabajo de calidad y a aprender a innovar. Esto no para copiar sino para aprovechar las ventajas que tenemos hoy en día, donde las fronteras ya no existen y estamos rodeados de  una avalancha de información por todos lados. Así como los equipos de la copa del mundo, trabajemos en equipo hacia objetivos en común y dejemos de un lado el pensar únicamente en el bien individual, cuando está en nosotros el forjar el futuro de nuestro país.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Traveling to Bogota? Here are my recommendations part 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://jcruiz.co/blog/2014/03/02/traveling-to-bogota-here-are-my-recommendations-part-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-02T17:06:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jcruiz.co/blog/2014/03/02/traveling-to-bogota-here-are-my-recommendations-part-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been asked in various occasions for recommendations and tips when traveling to Colombia. The people that know me, are aware that I talk a lot about Colombia and about my life growing in Bogota. </p>

<p>Conversations about Colombia, often end up in someone knowing someone that have been to Colombia or is planning to go to Colombia. And often, I end up volunteering to provide tips, guidance to get what I consider, an awesome experience while in my Country.</p>

<p>So instead of continuing sending out individual messages with recommendations about Colombia, why not posting them out there in the Internet so other could potentially find them? So here they are, let’s start with my city: Bogota
<!--more-->
Bogota is a very large city that much like any other major city in the world like NYC, Paris or Sao Paulo is live 24x7. These days the traffic has been really bad so be prepared to spend time in traffic jams, so avoid as much as you can to move around during peak times. 7 - 9 a.m in the mornings and 4-7 at night.</p>

<p>If you have a smarthphone with an active data plan on your phone. I encourage you to download <a href="http://tappsi.co/">Tappsi</a>, so you can order taxis in a similar way to Lift or Uber in a secure and confortable way. Also, <a href="https://www.uber.com/cities/bogota">Uber</a> is active in Bogota and the prices similar to the US.</p>

<p>I’m going to start covering those areas in the city that are located in the northen part:</p>

<h3 id="usaquen">Usaquen</h3>
<p style="text-align: center; font-weight: bold;">What used to be a small town located in the outskirts of the city, it's now a neighborhood. Though it is one of the most vibrant areas where you can find great restaurants and bars. You could literally try different things in every visit.</p>
<p>{% img http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v204/juanchoruiz/blog/usaquen_zpsbfe09de2.jpg %}</p>

<p>Recommendations:<br />
Usaquen has a famous flea market on Sundays where you can experience the great diversity of Bogota and buy really good handcrafts and souvenirs. Also right next to Usaquen there is a nice shopping mall-Hacienda Santa Barbara.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Antara: Peruvian food.</li>
  <li>80 sillas: Fusion international.</li>
  <li>Abasto: Organic/colombian food, great for brunch.</li>
  <li>Bogota Beer company: Drinks, social fun times.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="parque-93">Parque 93</h3>
<p style="text-align: center; font-weight: bold;">A park in the north that is surrounded by nice bars and restaurants. A great place to go for dinner + drinks/party</p>
<p>{% img http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v204/juanchoruiz/blog/93_zps71f8cfa8.jpg %}</p>

<p>Recommendations:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Salto del Angel: Dinner + party</li>
  <li>Sagal: Steak house</li>
  <li>Bogota Beer company</li>
  <li>Wok: Asian fusion</li>
  <li>La Hamburgueseria: Burgers + live music</li>
  <li>El corral: If you like hamburgers, you <strong>HAVE TO</strong> try El Corral, the best burgers in the world</li>
  <li>La bonga del sinu: Colombian style stake house</li>
  <li>Kukaramakara: Party</li>
  <li>Gaira Cafe: Northern Colombian food + party</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="zona-t">Zona T</h3>
<p style="text-align: center; font-weight: bold;">Is Bogota's version of San Francisco's Union Square. Upscale shopping + tons of alternatives to eat and party</p>
<p>{% img http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v204/juanchoruiz/blog/zonaT_zps0aaf280e.jpg %}</p>

<p>Recommendations:</p>

<ul>
  <li>La Plaza de Andres: Great food from all over Colombia</li>
  <li>14 Incas: Peruvian</li>
  <li>La mona: After-party food</li>
  <li>Andres DC: One of the best parties in the city you can get food there as well</li>
  <li>Cachao: Mojitos + live salsa</li>
  <li>Brasserie: French</li>
  <li>Armando Records: Alternative music, live bands, party</li>
  <li>Club Colombia: Upscale colombian food</li>
  <li>Wabisabi: Japanese</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="zona-g">Zona G</h3>
<p style="text-align: center; font-weight: bold;">Established as one of the fastest growing areas for new and upscale restaurants in the city.</p>
<p>{% img http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v204/juanchoruiz/blog/zonag_zps890c7f10.jpg %}</p>

<p>Recommendations:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Astrid y Gaston: Peruvian</li>
  <li>La Bagatelle: French</li>
  <li>La Cigale: Frech</li>
  <li>La Biferia: Steakhouse</li>
  <li>Masa: Bakery, coffee</li>
  <li>Nazca: Peruvian</li>
</ul>

<p>Part 2 with other areas of the city comming up soon…</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
