<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: hacking | The Other Radio]]></title>
  <link href="http://young-bastion-9487.herokuapp.com//blog/categories/hacking/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://young-bastion-9487.herokuapp.com//"/>
  <updated>2014-02-19T14:57:53-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://young-bastion-9487.herokuapp.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Juan Camilo Ruiz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blogging Like a Hacker]]></title>
    <link href="http://young-bastion-9487.herokuapp.com//blog/2013/08/30/blogging-like-a-hacker/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-30T13:30:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://young-bastion-9487.herokuapp.com//blog/2013/08/30/blogging-like-a-hacker</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My old blogs used well known blogging engines: blogger and MovableType. For years blogger has been able to keep up with trends &ndash; in my opinion always catching up. However, I didn&rsquo;t want to simply create a new blog on blogger; something was just not right.</p>

<p>One day a technical blog cought my attention because of its look and feel and nice caligraphy. It was <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> which was created under the premise that is a blogging framework for hackers.</p>

<p>So, what does it reallly mean? Let me give you more context info:</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I come from the Java EE world &ndash; so IDEs, frameworks, installing appication servers, compiling and running &ndash; are all very well known to me. However when I joined <a href="http://moovweb.com">Moovweb</a> I realized something that I had been seeing for a while: the new companies are not sold by Java or .Net anymore.</p>

<p>In other words, outside of the traditional corporate world developers don&rsquo;t talk anymore about enterprise EJBs, Controllers or JSF, and instead the dictionary words sound something like Go, JavaScript, Ruby, HTML 5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, Angular, etc&hellip;.</p>

<p>The new era of enterprise software is already here and it is rapidly taking over the traditional way that, not too long ago for some of us, were the latest trends in programming: objects oriented, MVC, JSPs (specially) &hellip;. and I thought that at that point I knew it all.</p>

<p>So how all of the above connects with blogging? Well, I just told you about my developer journey and where I&rsquo;m right now so, as part of my new life:</p>

<ul>
<li>I&rsquo;m getting used to not having and IDE or ultra editor to create Java applications or blog posts.</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m changing Java systax for Tritium, Uranium, Javascript, markdown and Sass.</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m getting used to using GitHub for pushing my code and also pushing my entire blog.</li>
<li>And, finally I&rsquo;m using Heroku to host this blog that you are reading right now</li>
</ul>


<p>So yeah, this is one of my new hacking projects&hellip;.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
