<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: product management | The Other Radio]]></title>
  <link href="http://jcruiz.co/blog/categories/product-management/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jcruiz.co/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-26T02:13:36-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://jcruiz.co/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Juan Camilo Ruiz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2014 The Year of Scrum...]]></title>
    <link href="http://jcruiz.co/blog/2015/02/26/2014-the-year-of-scrum-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-26T02:12:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jcruiz.co/blog/2015/02/26/2014-the-year-of-scrum-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s been a while since my last post. With Q1 of 2015 almost over, it’s long overdue to have a new post out the door. I started this post at the end of 2014, but finally I’m taking the time to complete it and publish it.</p>

<p>2014 was a really interesting and enlightening year for my product management career.  It marked the year that I got fully exposed to the rollout of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scrum_%28software_development%29">Scrum</a> within my organization from scratch and that now, a year later, has helped me and my team to be more organized on how the way that we built software.
<!--more-->
##Why did we chose Scrum?
After going through a tortuous project of re-architecting some of the major building blocks from our Platform, we touched bottom. Many things factor-in to make the perfect storm which overall damaged the team morale and left us with many things that needed to be fixed.</p>

<p>One of my colleagues and friend had prior experience with Scrum, he became the champion of Scrum and later our scrum master. He made sure that not the just the team and management were on board with the initiative, but also, he made sure that we didn’t take the “easy” and short way of making everything ourselves without the proper training. </p>

<blockquote>
  <p><em>Lesson No.1: Don’t take shortcuts, a lot of companies start with the wrong foot, yet by the time is known, it’s already too late</em></p>
</blockquote>

<p>However, by the time we had training, the team was familiar with the basics of Scrum principles and even have had some <a href="https://www.scrum.org/scrumbut">“Scrum but”</a> sprints. That helped us to make the most out of the training. But same as with the school, one thing is the theory and one thing is the practice.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><em>Lesson No.2: Do the homework before hand, come prepare and ask as many questions as possible</em></p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="what-has-happened-a-year-later">What has happened a year later?</h2>
<p>In the same way that the whole process started organically, we as team started adapting Scrum to our organization, making all kinds of adjustments like: sprint duration, estimation, story points, how we run demos and retrospectives, definition of done, managing escalations…, and the list goes on and on.</p>

<p>Up until know we have what I consider a strong practice that is the sum of all the different adjustments, mentioned before and that by no means, keeps evolving. </p>

<p>The major aspects from our current Sprint process circle around the respect for the engineer’s time and the high cost associated with switching contexts. It puts a big responsibility on Product to make all the necessary due diligence required to define, scope and prioritize what goes into a Sprint. It’s build on transparency, knowledge sharing and keeping honest to ourselves acknowledging the areas of improvement and taking actions to correct what is going in the wrong direction and, excel those things that we are doing well so we can continue doing them.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><em>Lesson No.3 There has to be a continuous improvement on processes and methods that lead to better results and higher team morale</em></p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="what-are-the-major-challenges">What are the major challenges</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Releasing often and maintain momentum over features</li>
  <li>On Product: Keep a healthy backlog and prioritize in the best possible way in an ocean of requirements (<em>see this article: http://www.forbes.com/sites/kylewong/2015/02/13/your-startup-is-overwhelmed-with-product-requests-now-what/</em>)</li>
  <li>Pruning the icebox</li>
  <li>People over processes </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="my-list-of-benefits-from-scrum">My list of Benefits from Scrum</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Streamlined and organized product development cycle</li>
  <li>Shared knowledge</li>
  <li>Clear definition of roles, clear distinction over engineering vs product</li>
  <li>Constant collaboration</li>
  <li>Constant feedback recollection</li>
  <li>Understanding the art of prioritization</li>
  <li>Mastering JIRA</li>
  <li>Easier communication with other parts from the organization</li>
  <li>Getting things done</li>
  <li>Move the needle forward. </li>
</ul>

<p>Expect more shared opinions from the journey into the Product Management waters. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
